hiusa.org 2015-09-05

# HI USA | Hostelling International USA | HI Hostels Reservations

## Privacy Policy 

This document outlines Hostelling International USA's (HI-USA) online privacy policy, which governs personal information gathered on the national web site www.hiusa.org and its aliases.

**HI-USA Commitment to Online Security**  
Physical, electronic and managerial procedures have been employed to safeguard the security and integrity of personal information. Billing information is encrypted whenever transmitted or received online. Personal information is accessible only by staff or volunteers designated to handle online enquiries, purchases or complaints. All HI-USA agents and contractors with access to personal information obtained on the HI-USA web site are also bound to adhere to this policy. 

**Personal Information that HI-USA May Collect Online**  
When an individual makes a purchase or places a reservation with HI-USA online, HI-USA may collect the following types of personal information: name, age, postal and e-mail addresses, telephone numbers, facsimile numbers and billing information. HI-USA may also collect other demographic or psychographic information through member surveys and program participation with their consent.

**How HI-USA Uses Personal Information Collected Online**  
Unless you consent, we will not use your personal information for any purpose other than that for which it is submitted. We use personal information to reply to enquiries, complete a transaction, manage complaints, provide operational notices and in program recordkeeping. HI-USA membership entitles the purchaser to certain benefits, including access to hostels, discounts and communications from HI-USA and its local affiliates. HI-USA is a tax-exempt, not for profit organization that relies on individual contributions to fund operations and directly solicits its membership for this purpose. HI-USA will provide its members with the opportunity to opt out of receiving various membership benefits, communications and solicitations. Election boxes appear as part of individual communications and solicitations. At any time you can add or remove your name from an HI-USA list by contacting us at [webmaster@hiusa.org](mailto:webmaster@hiusa.org).

**How Your Information May Be Shared**  
In order to process an enquiry, transaction or complaint, HI-USA may send information to the International Youth Hostel Federation (IYHF), a National association affiliate, a HI-USA Council, a hostel or other a relevant third party service or program supplier. HI-USA will not sell or rent your personal information to any third party. HI-USA wil not give direct access to any third party for the distribution of information or a given product or service offer, without being coordinated through HI-USA.

HI-USA may also release personal information to appropriate governmental authorities under the following circumstances: 

  * Where release is required by law (for example, a subpoena) or regulation, or is requested by a government agency conducting investigations or proceedings; 
  * Where our records indicate a member or participant may be engaged in fraudulent activity or other deceptive practices that a governmental agency should be made aware of.
  * Where your communication suggests possible harm to others.

**Help Us Keep Your Personal Information Accurate**  
If your personal information changes or you would like to review the personal information we may have on file, please e-mail us with the new information or your review request at webmaster@hiusa.org. Let us also know the HI-USA program, product or service that led to your submission of personal information so we may efficiently locate your information.

**Computer Tracking and Cookies**  
Our web sites do track sessions and employ analytics. However, we do not collect or distribute personal information not entered by visitors. Our site logs do generate certain kinds of non-identifying site usage data, such as the number of hits and visits. This information is used for internal purposes by technical support staff to provide better services to the public and may also be provided to others in the form or aggregate traffic reports, but such statistics contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information.

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. HI-USA uses non-identifying cookies to provide easier site navigation and access to forms. You can still use the HI-USA site if your browser is set to reject cookies. Our cookies do not generate personal data, do not read personal data from your machine and are never tied to anything that could be used to identify you.

If you have a complaint about HI-USA's compliance with this privacy policy, you may contact us at [webmaster@hiusa.org](mailto:webmaster@hiusa.org).
